Contact

London, United Kingdom +447384866952 (Mobile) damasojonald@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jonalddamaso (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Test-Driven Development
TypeScript
API Testing

Certifications

Introduction to Cybersecurity Tools

Cybersecurity Compliance Framework & System Administration

Cybersecurity Capstone: Breach Response Case Studies

IBM Cybersecurity Analyst Specialization

Network Security & Database Vulnerabilities

Jonald Damaso

Web Developer and Cybersecurity Analyst. No visa requirement and open to relocation.

London Area, United Kingdom

Summary

My experience as a web developer and quality assurance specialist honed my skills in project management, client communications and attention to detail. I am passionate about continuous learning which is why I undertook an internship program in the UK and obtained a Cybersecurity Analyst certification whilst on extended paternity leave. I'm a very proud father and taking care of my son taught me more about humility, patience, attention to detail, time management and teaching.

Experience

Tech Returners
Frontend Developer
January 2023 - Present (6 months)
Manchester Area, United Kingdom

The Cartland's Group Junior Web Developer April 2020 - July 2020 (4 months) United Kingdom

I was involved in several projects within travel and media industry, featuring elements of both front-end design and back-end development. My responsibilities included redesigning and improving the website of the London Magical Tours, where I used WordPress, HTML5, and CSS3.

FastTrackSolutions, Inc.
Full Stack Web Developer
February 2019 - October 2019 (9 months)
Manila, Philippines

Prior to joining my wife in the UK, I made a career switch (from quality assurance to web developing - my passion!) and carried the skills I learned in my early career - attention to detail, project management and client communications.

In Fasttrack, I was mainly responsible for the design, testing, development and deployment of cloud-based accounting software, using Javascript, HTML and PHP. I also went on fieldwork to provide client support during and after the software implementation.

AffinityX Quality Assurance Specialist April 2013 - March 2018 (5 years) Manila, Philippines

This role involved reviewing the work of graphic designers and junior quality analysts to ensure that the advertising products meet the specifications of our US-based customers. I also contributed to the improvement of the quality assurance process of the company and to training junior quality analysts.

The DDC Group Quality Controller and Trainer March 2008 - December 2012 (4 years 10 months) Mandaluyong City, Philippines

My role involved providing quality assurance services for companies within the shipping industry. This included reviewing the work performed by a separate internal team based in the US and ensuring that freight documents meet customer specifications. I also contributed to the improvement of the quality assurance process of the company and in training junior quality analysts.

Education

AMG Technological College College Degree, Information Technology · (2006 - 2009)

Zuitt - Coding Bootcamp Philippines
Certification, Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information Resources
Design · (2018 - 2018)